What I want to do in this video is talk a little bit more about forms in React Native,
在本视频中 我将深入讲解下 React Native 中的表单
and specifically this text input component and this switch component.
具体而言是这个 TextInput 组件和 Switch 组件
So on our state,
在我们的 state 中
what I want to do is let's go ahead and add some properties here.
在这里添加一些属性
Say inputs which will just be my Twitter handle and we will say,
输入 input 和我的推特帐号
show input and set that to false.
输入 showInput 设为 false
So what we want our UI to look like is,
我们希望我们的 UI
we want a little switch button that when it's on,
能出现一个切换按钮
we show the text input that we can change.
该按钮开启时 显示可以更改的输入文本
Once off, we hide it.
关闭时 则隐藏文本
So what we will do here is,
在这里
let's go ahead and first render the switch component.
首先渲染 Switch 组件
And we need to pass it, two different things.
需要传入两项不同的内容
The first thing we're going to pass it is the value and
首先传入 value
the second thing is the function that's going to be called when we press it.
其次传入点击按钮时将调用的函数
So what we're going to do,
我们在这里
let's go ahead and destructure both of our properties on our states.
对我们的 state 解构这两项属性
And then, we need to go ahead and create a handle toggle switch function.
然后创建一个 handleToggleSwitch 函数
And again, what this is going to do is it's going to be responsible
该函数的作用是
for updating the switch states.
负责更新切换开关状态
So what we can do here is,
在这里
we can say show input,
输入 showInput
is going to be the opposite of whatever it currently is.
它将是当前状态的对立状态
So whenever this function runs,
每当运行该函数时
switch input is going to toggle.
switch 输入将切换
So now what we can do is we can come in here and say,
在这里输入
value is going to be show input.
value =
And on value change,
然后输入 onValueChange
we're going to go ahead and give it the start handle toggle switch.
设为 this.handleToggleSwitch
So now, what's going to happen,
现在转到应用界面
is you'll notice in our UI,
你会在应用界面上
we have this toggle switch button right here.
看到这个切换按钮
And we can toggle on and off,
可以开启或关闭
which is updating this show input property on our state.
它会对我们的 state 更新该 showInput 属性
And so now, what we need to do is actually add in our text input.
现在我们需要添加 TextInput
So what we're going to do is we'll say,
并输入
if show input and equal to true then what we want to do,
如果 showInput 为 true
is we want to show this text input component.
则显示这个 TextInput 组件
And we actually want to be able to change the text input,
我们实际上希望能更改这个 TextInput
obviously, so we need to do a few more things.
因此需要再设置几项内容
We can give it the input itself.
提供 input 本身
We can give it some style,
设定一些样式
which I have created down here below, if you didn't see those.
我在下面创建了这些样式
And then what we're going to give it is a function that
然后提供一个当它改变时
will be called whenever it changed so we can update our local state.
将被调用的函数 这样就能更新本地状态
So we'll say, start handle text change and then handle
输入 this.handleTextChange
text change is going to be a method on a component and what it's going to do,
handleTextChange 将为组件上的一个方法
is it's going to receive the brand new input and then,
它将接收崭新的 input
it's also going to call set state.
还将调用 setState
And then, what it is going to do is it's going to just update the input.
然后它将更新 input
So now, when we run this,
现在运行代码
when we click toggle on,
点击该开关
you'll notice that we get this input.
你会看到该输入内容
And then, we can now come in here and we can change the input.
我们可以更改该输入内容
So what happens if,
如果我们想向用户界面上
say we wanted to add an image to our UI.
添加图片呢？
So let's say right here,
假设这里
we had an image,
有个图片
let's import our image component.
导入 image 组件
So everything looks pretty much the same.
一切看起来几乎一样
A toggle on the input.
具有输入切换按钮
But now what happens when I click on the text input,
但是现在点击文本输入框的话
you'll notice that the keyboard came up and it actually hid the input,
出现了键盘 并且将输入框隐藏起来了
which isn't really a good idea.
这样不太合适
So what we can do to avoid that,
避免方法很简单
is React Native has this keyboard avoiding view component.
React Native 提供了这个 this keyboardAvoidingView 组件
So instead of having view here,
我们可以将这里的 View
what we can do, is we can change that out with keyboard avoiding view.
替换为 keyboardAvoidingView
And then we can give it a behavior prop,
并为其提供 behavior 属性
and we will just say padding.
设为 padding
That's going to specify how the view is going to avoid the keyboard.
指明该视图如何不被键盘遮盖
We'll just go ahead and add some padding around it.
我们将在其周围添加一些内边距
So now what will happen, is we toggle on the input field.
现在开启输入字段的话
We hit that and you'll notice that instead of hiding the input field,
你会发现输入字段没有被隐藏
the whole view rose.
整个视图都能看见
And now we still see the keyboard,
依然能看到键盘
but we also still see the input field.
并且能看到输入字段